Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets, circa 1860-circa 1970; K0001 Series 4; 18 linear feet (Box 14, Box 11, Box 16, Box 15, Box 10, Box 51, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 18, Box 45, Box 46, Box 49, Box 2, Box 1, Box 53, Box 52, Box 48, Box 6, Box 17, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  - Concerning the Jews, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Mark Twain. Originally published in 1899. New York, London: Harper and Brothers Publishers, 1934. Donated with correspondence and an article from Mildred Leo Clemens, cousin of Samuel Clemens (Mark Twain), to Pauline (Mrs. Hugo) Rosenberg. Clemmens also inscribed the pamphlet to Rosenberg, along with comments on the subject of the pamphlet. The letter is housed with the pamphlet.
  - Library resources for Jewish studies in the United States, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Reprinted from the American Jewish Yearbook (1974-75)
  - New York's World's Fair program, 4/1939 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Dedication of the Jewish Palestine pavilion by Albert Einstein, 05/28/1939 (Box 1, Folder 61.01)
    Donated with program from the 1939 New York World's Fair (multiple copies).
  - Haym Salomon, the patriot broker of the Revolution, his real achievements and their exaggeration, an open letter to Congressman Celler, 02/26/1931 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Short guide to the excavations of Ramat Rahel, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Palestine book news, 05/1948 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Judaica, silver, pewter, brass and other ritual objects, 12/15/1966 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Edward D. Coleman, librarian and bibliographer 1892-1939, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Reprinted from the Bulletin of The New York Public Library Vol. 63 No. 8
  - The Sinai pulpit, vol. 4, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - The Sinai pulpit, vol. 2, 1963 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    A selection of sermons delivered from the pulpit of Sinai Temple, including one after the assassination of President John F. Kennedy.
  - The Dubno maggid, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Reprinted from the Hebrew Union College Annual Vol. 23 part 2, 1950-51
  - Judas, the beloved executioner, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Contains obituary from the New York Times 1965. Is inscribed to Rabbi Kiev. Reprinted from the Psychoanalytic Quarterly vol. 23, 1960
  - A letter of Maimonides to R. Joseph Ibn Aknin, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Reprinted from Tradition: A Journal of Orthodox Jewish Thought Vol. 5 No. 2, Spring 1963
  - Exercises in celebration of the two hundred and fiftieth anniversary of the settlement of the Jews in the United States, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bloch books, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Members Catalog Fall-Winter 1974-75 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - The Israel book publishers' bulletin, 03/1967 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Sabra books Fall 1970 catalog (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - A catalogue of the library of Jewish studies, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Antiquariaat Spinoza, catalogue 8, early Judaism, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - The Jewish Publication Society of America members catalog Spring/Summer, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Judaica and vetus testamentum, catalogue no. 447, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Dutch and English
  - The Society for Old Testament Study book list, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Books on the ancient Near East, 07/1969 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    Dutch, German and English
  - Catalogue 47: history of the Jews, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Selected list, 11/1968 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - 1974 catalog: Judaica, Biblica, Hebraica (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Bloch's bookstore bulletin, Fall 1969 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - The Jewish contribution to civilization, catalogue no. 144, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Ladino books in the Library of Congress, a bibliography, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - General catalogue, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Tzaddikim 5, a supplement to tzaddikim 4, a catalogue and biblioraphy fo specialized Judaic books, Spring/Summer 1975 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Tzaddikim, a catalogue of chassidic, kabbalistic and selected Judaic books, Fall 1973/74 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Catalogue, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - The modern Jewish experience, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Selected paperbound books of Jewish interest, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Members catalog, new books and complete backlist, Fall 1973 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - List of publications, 1974-75 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Catalogue no. 411, ancient Near East including some Judaica, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Goldston's catalogue no. 21, catalogue of an important collection of Hebraica and Judaica, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - List of publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Biblical institute press, catalogo generale, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Catalogue 82, rare and unusual books relating to Asia including an important section on Palestine, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Rudolf Steiner, works on the science and of the spirit anthroposophy, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - The Magnes Press list of publications, 1929-1969, 03/1969 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Over a century of service, Bloch's book bulletin, vol. 38 nos. 162-163, Fall 1967 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Members catalog, January, February, March, new books and complete backlist, Winter 1973 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Catalogue 177, bibliography and literary history, Hebraica and Judaica, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Ktav chanukah gift catalogue, 1973 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Catalogue 159, early Hebrew books, undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Catalogue 270, Hebraica Judaeo-German Judaica, undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Catalog 236, the Bible, part 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Judaica book sale catalogue, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Awards catalogue, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - List 173: history of the Jews, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    English and German
  - List 175, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Bloch's book bulletin, 03/1963 - 04/1963 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Books of Jewish and Zionist interest recommended by the education department of Hadassah, Fall 1956 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Catalog: Judaica, Biblica, Hebraica, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Bloch's book bulletin, Fall-Winter publications of Judaica and Hebraica, 12/1957 - 02/1958 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Supplement to Bloch's book bulletin, 02/1957 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Catalogue no. 59, 06/1969 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - The Society for Old Testament Study book list, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - The pleistocene of the central Jordan valley the excavations at 'Ubeidiya, undated (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Important Hebrew books, 05/30/1972 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - The Ancient Near East and Judaica, fourteen recent publications, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - List 164, bibliography and history of Jewish studies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Catalogue 57, the Jews in France, undated (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Catalogue no. 34, 10/1957 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Catalog 240, the Bible, commentaries, undated (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - The Solomon Rosenthal collection, 11/1942 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Judaica orientalia/theology and related subjects, catalogue no. 41, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Jewish coins, auction sale April 3, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Microcard catalogue of rare Hebrew codices, manuscripts and ancient prints in the Kaufmann collection, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Jerusalem, dedicated to the struggle of nineteen centuries waged by the Jewish people from the time that the temple was destroyed to the time that the Knesset --Israel's parliament-- was formally opened in the holy city of Jerusalem, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Catalogue of Hebrew literature, Fall 1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Hebrew
  - Catalogue no. 12, Judaica, undated (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Catalog, undated (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - List 163, bibliography and booklore, undated (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Conference on the status of Soviet Jews, undated (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Report of the United Nations Palestine Commision to the second special session of the general assembly, 04/10/1948 (Box 2, Folder 179)
  - The Jewish Historical Society of England, 03/1966 (Box 2, Folder 181)
  - Art in the Jewish tradition, undated (Box 2, Folder 277)
  - The book of life, 09/09/1970 (Box 2, Folder 460)
  - Zwei Flugblatter den "Klever Getstreit" betreffend, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 594)
    Facsimiles of two proclamations by the rabbinates of Frankfurt am Main and Mannheim concerning the divorce case of Isaac Neuberg and Lea Gunzenhauser, in 1766
  - Igud ha-artsi shel ha-emune ha-bama ha musikah veha-mahal: Hisadrut ha-kelalit shel ha-ovdim ha-Ivrim be-Erets-Yisrael, 10/1953 - 12/1953 (Box 2, Folder 621)
  - B[et] M[esoher] sefarim "Zohar"; Nahlat Benyamin 3 tel Aviv, 1963 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 641)
  - Reshimat kitve Yad (number 9) shel bet eked ha-sefarim shel harav hatsadik ha-meforsum R. Nahum Dov Friedman, 1900 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 644)
  - Davar ha-shavua: musaf erev-Shabat shel "Davar", 03/27/1947 (Box 2, Folder 652)
  - Davar ha shavua: 50, 05/22/1947 (Box 2, Folder 653)
  - Davar ha shavua: 65, 09/04/1947 (Box 2, Folder 654)
  - Davar ha shavua: 88, 02/19/1948 (Box 2, Folder 655)
  - Davar ha shavua: 114, 08/19/1948 (Box 2, Folder 656)
  - Davar ha shavua: 115, 08/26/1948 (Box 2, Folder 657)
  - Davar ha shavua: 126, 11/18/1948 (Box 2, Folder 658)
  - Davar ha shavua: 132, 12/30/1948 (Box 2, Folder 659)
  - Davar ha shavua: 134, 01/13/1949 (Box 2, Folder 660)
  - Davar ha shavua: 135, 01/20/1949 (Box 2, Folder 661)
  - Davar ha shavua: 146, 04/12/1949 (Box 2, Folder 662)
  - Davar ha shavua: 150, 05/19/1949 (Box 2, Folder 663)
  - Davar ha shavua, 158, 07/15/1949 (Box 2, Folder 664)
  - Davar ha shavua: 161, 08/04/1949 (Box 2, Folder 665)
  - Davar ha shavua: 146, 04/21/1949 (Box 2, Folder 667)
  - Leket mi-tokh ha-itonut: 18, 06/1971 - 07/1971 (Box 2, Folder 668)
  - Maariv: 19-21 September 1969, 09/19/1969 (Box 2, Folder 669)
  - Set of copperplate engravings by Johann Georg Puschner from Paul Christian Kirchner's Jdisches Ceremoniel (most likely the 1724 edition published by Peter Conrad Monath in Nuremberg), c. 1724 (Box 2, Folder 1489)
  - Ad hoc committee on the Palestinian question, report of sub-commitee 1, 11/14/1947 (Box 2, Folder 1501)
  - Ad hoc committee on the Palestine question, report of sub-committee 2, 11/11/1947 (Box 2, Folder 1502)
  - An evidence bill for Israel, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1589)
  - Newsletter on Israel religious and cultural affairs, Who is a Jew? Final Act of Drama., 03/1970 (Box 2, Folder 1590)
  - Music of the operetta "broken violin" in Themoashefsky's National Theatre, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1607)
  - Idishe Muzik = Jewish music nu. 1, 7/1934 (Box 2, Folder 1612)
    Sheet music in Yiddish and English
  - Oklahoma: vocal section, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1613)
  - Album of songs by Victor Herbert with lyrics by well known authors, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1614)
  - Ba-Mahneh, 11/24/1970 (Box 2, Folder 1615)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 37, 04/11/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1616)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 38, 04/25/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1617)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 32, 03/07/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1618)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 21, 12/20/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1619)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 34, 03/21/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1620)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 42, gil. 42, 05/23/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1621)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 40, 05/09/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1622)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 39, 05/02/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1623)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 41, 05/16/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1624)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 33, 03/14/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1625)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 30, 2/21/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1626)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 26, 01/24/1946 (Box 2, Folder 1627)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil. 14, 11/01/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1628)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 3, gil.11, 10/11/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1629)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2, gil.38, 06/21/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1630)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2, gil. 37, 06/07/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1631)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2, gil. 36, 05/31/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1632)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2, gil. 31, 04/26/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1633)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2, gil. 26, 03/15/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1634)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2; gil. 27, 3/22/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1635)
  - ha-Galgal: kerekh 2; gil. 28, 3/28/1945 (Box 2, Folder 1636)
  - The Leo W. Gilbert collection of the doar ivri issue of Israel, 03/03/1971 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - The book chest, Hebraica and Judaica... the scholars approach, undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Some recent aquisitions, publications by faculty and alumni HUC-JIR, Spring 1964 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Geniza manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Judaica, Hebrew manuscripts and books ritual silver and other objects, 05/25/1972 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Judaica, 12/16/1965 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Catalogue of books on Palestine and Zionism, Fall and Winter, 1948-49, 1948 - 1949 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Catalogue of the library of the late Rabbi Emanuel Eckstein of Cleveland, undated (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Second and last session, 02/29/1940 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Catalogue of an important library of Hebraica formed on the continent of North America, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Judaica, gold, silver, pewter & brass ceremonial objects, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - The league for abolishment of religious coercion in Israel, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Anglo-Jewish art and history, Spring 1969 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - The Hebrew University Jerusalem, general information, undated (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Have you seen? Books of special interest from the Judaica collection, Boston public library, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Issues: Winter 1961 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Installation service for Rev. Dr. Julius Mark as senior rabbi of Congregation Emanu-El of the City of New York, 09/24/1948 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - A statement prepared by George Alexander Kohut, executive director, undated (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - The Jewish historical society of England, undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Institute for the research of Jewish communities in the Middle East, 5/1949 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Meetings of the Jewish Historical Society of England, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Jewish occupational bulletin, vol. 1, no. 11, 4/1942 - 5/1942 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Jewish occupational bulletin, vol 1, no. 10, 03/1942 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Jewish studies of peace and post-war problems, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    Reprint from Contemporary Jewish Record, April 1941
  - God's fools, sixteen discourses, 1923 - 1924 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - News letter, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Ismar Elbogen, 1874-1943, a bibliography, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    Reprinted from Historia Judaica, vol. 8, no. 1, April 1946
  - Hermann Cohen, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    Reprinted from Historia Judaica, 1942. Signed by the author.
  - Inauguration ceremony of the president of the state, Zalman Shazar, as honorary president of the Historical Society of Israel, 12/15/1964 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - The university Jewish voice, vol. 2, no. 3, 02/1971 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - BJE bulletin, no. 150, Fall 1970 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Prayer when going on a voyage, undated (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Brotherhood, vol. 5, no. 4, 03/1972 - 04/1972 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Brotherhood, vol. 5, no. 2, 11/1971 - 12/1971 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Evening service for Israel independence day, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - The image of the Jews, 11/21/1968 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - About the book... "friends of the Oscar Hillel Plotkin library", undated (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - The Jewish Review (Jevrejski pregled), no. 7-8, 07/1974 - 08/1974 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - The Jewish review (Jevresjski pregled), no. 3-4, 03/1973 - 04/1973 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - The survival of the Chinese Jews, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Free Synagogue of Westchester memorial service for Rabbi Max Maccoby, 03/03/1957 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Archaeological Newsletter, no. 8, 02/1954 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - A bibliography of Maimonides, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - Catalogue of pamphlets on Palestine and Zionism, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - Catalogue of the Hebrew Union College, Cincinnati, 1941 - 1942 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    Includes illustrated insert concerning Isaac Mayer Wise
  - Madrich hakashrus 5729 for pessach and the whole year, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - List of institutions and key to abbreviations, undated (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - You and Judaism, vol. 5, no. 3, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - A book list for the Jewish adult, undated (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - Jewish bookplates of Dutch interest, undated (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Joint documentary projects announcing the publication of the "guide to Jewish history under Nazi impact," by Jacob Robinson and Philip Friedman, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - Answers and questions, Israel and Egypt, Summer 1971 (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - A record of American zionism, 05/1956 (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Faith and doubt, undated (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - Synopsis of Mr. C.G. Montefiore's Paper on "the importance of liberal Judaism for the religious life", 08/19/1928 (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - The meaning of the "house of the book", 07/22/1973 (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - Britain speaks, 09/20/1941 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    Broadcast to Canada and the United States
  - Addresses in honor of the seventy-fifth birthday of Solomon B. Freehof, 11/05/1967 (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - Seek great things: an address by Jerome R. Malino, 03/14/1952 (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - Personal Judaism, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    Delivered on Yom Kippur Eve at Temple Beth El and broadcast on WJR on Tuesday evening, October 1, 1968
  - Service in appreciation of American ideals (commemorating the birthdates of Washington and Lincoln), undated (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - Message of the president to the thirty-eighth annual convention of the Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - High holy day sermon seminar, 09/1961 (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - Breathe upon these slain and they shall live, undated (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - New light on the eternal book, 05/05/1957 (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - A generation of founders, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - An undelivered address to the leaving students of the Jewish Institute of Religion at New York, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - Nation, people, religion: what are we?, 10/16/1943 (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - What sins shall we confess, 09/14/1956 (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - The future of human community, 06/05/1968 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - Divorce in Jewish law, no. 1, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    Reprinted from the "Journal of Comparative Legislation."
  - The religion of the home, 04/03/1931 (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - If a rabbi is to live, 06/08/1968 (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - The new paths: whither do they lead?, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1930 - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    Includes, "Ahad Ha'am," by Deborah Pessin, "Theodor Herzl," by Deborah Pessin, "Moses Hess," by Deborah Pessin, "Chaim Weizmann," by Deborah Pessin, "Professor Zebi (Hermann) Schapira," by G. Menahem, "Ahad Ha'am--Nationalist," by Jacob S. Golub, "Hayyim Nahman Bialik," by Israel Efros, "A.D. Gordon," by Joseph Aaronovitch and Samuel Dayan and "Rabbi and Mathematician: The Life of Hermann Schapira," by Leib Jaffe.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1928 - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    Includes "The Zionist Movement," "Zionism: Its Aims and Achievements," by the Zionist Organization of America, "Observations on the Report of the Palestine Royal Commission," by Cyrus Adler, "To the Jewish Youth: Address of Dr. Chaim Arlosoroff," published by The Zionist Labor Party "Hitachduth" of America and Canada, "Jewish Achievements in Palestine," published by the Jewish Agency for Palestine "Jewish Immigration into Palestine," by David Ben-Gurion, "Recent Progress in Palestine," by Israel Cohen, "Land and Destiny," by Dr. Solomon Goldman, "Justice Not Tolerance," by Solomon Goldman, "Revolutionary Constructivism: Essays on the Jewish Labor Movement in Palestine," published by Young Poale Zion Alliance, "Allgemeiner Zinoismus," by Dr. Felix Weltsch, "The Growth of Modern Hebrew Literature," by Hillel Bavli, "Zionism and the Jewish Youth of America," by Elias M. Epstein, "The Jordan: A New Frontier of Democracy," by Ira Eisenstein, "The Story of the Hebrew University in Jerusalem," by Joseph Klausner, "Some Principles of Jewish Education," by Dr. Jacob S. Golub, "Torah from Zion," by Eugene Kohn, and "The Place of Palestine in Modern Jewish Life," by Rabbi Milton Steinberg.
  - Bound reports regarding the British Mandate, 1922 - 1929 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    From "His Majesty's Stationery Office." Includes, "Palestine: Correspondence with the Palestine Arab Delegation and the Zionist Organisation, Presented to Parliament by Command of His Majesty," 1922, "Palestine: Papers Relating to the Elections foe the Palestine Legislative Council," 1923, "Palestine: Proposed Formation of An Arab Agency. Correspondence with the High Commissioner for Palestine," 1923, "Report of the Commission on the Palestine Disturbances of August, 1929," 1930, "Palestine: Statement with Regard to British Policy," 1930, "Report by His Britannic Majesty's Government on the Administration Under Mandate of Palestine and Transjordan for the Year 1924," 1925, "Report by His Britannic Majesty's Government to the Council of The League of Nations on the Administration of Palestine and Transjordan for the Year 1925," 1926, "Report by His Britannic Majesty's Government to the League of Nations on the Administration of Palestinian and Trans-Jordan for the Year 1926," 1927, "Report by His Britannic Majesty's Governments to the Council of the League of Nations on the Administration of Palestine and Trans-Jordan for the Year 1927," 1928, "Report by His Majesty's Government in the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland to the Council of The League of Nations on the Administration of Palestine and Trans-Jordan for the Year 1928," 1929
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1929 - 1940 (Box 3, Folder 217)
    Includes, "Lawrence of Arabia: Zionism and Palestine," 1940, by Sir Ronald Storrs, "British Imperial Interests in Palestine," 1937, by Herbert Sidebotham, "British Statesmen on the Palestine Land Transfers Regulations," 1940, published by American Zionist Bureau, "Documents and Correspondence Relating to Palestine, August 1939 to March 1940," 1940, published by the Jewish Agency for Palestine, "Promises and Afterthoughts: Notes on Certain White Papers Relating to the Palestine Conferences," May 1939, by Leonard Stein, "The Near East in European Politics," 1937, by Hans Kohn, "Partition or Zionism? The Fate of Palestine and the Jewish Home," May 1938, by Abraham Revusky, "Zionism adna the Recent Events in Palestine," October 1929, published by the Federation of Young Judaea of Canada.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1931 - 1939 (Box 3, Folder 218)
    Includes, "Allgemeiner Zionismus," n.d., by Dr. Felix Weltsch, "The Program of the Zionist Organization of America: Resolutions Adopted by the National Executive Committee," 1931, published by the Committee on Public Information of the Zionist Organization of America, "The Zionist Movement: Its Aspirations, Aims and Accomplishments," 1939, published by the Zionist Organization of America, "The Birth of Jewish Statesmanship: A Story of Theodor Herzl's Life," n.d., by Emanuel Neumann, "Forty Years of Zionism," n.d., by S.M. Melamed, "The Progress of Zionism," 1939, by Israel Cohen, " Hashomer: The First Jewish Watch in Palestine," 1939, by Lotta Levensohn, "Objections to Zionism Answered," 1937, published by the Zionist Organization of America.
  - Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society, no. 6. The oldest tombstone-inscriptions of Philadelphia and Richmond, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 299)
  - Zionist pamphlets, 1917 - 1932 (Box 4, Folder 219)